<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alberto Giust</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Alberto Giust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alright21.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mobile Security Introduction</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/blog/mobile_security/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/blog/mobile_security/</guid><description>Mobile Security Introduction Setup Every mobile assessment requires some different setup compared to web applications. In this guide, we will explain how to enter the beatiful world of mobile security, and not feel overwhelmed by do so.
Standard setup We need to set up our environment to proxy the requests coming from the mobile phone. Unfortunately, almost every application implements ssl pinning techniques to prevent this: the application uses some methods to check the server certificate against a whitelist, and allows communication only if the other end is trusted.</description></item><item><title>SrdnlenCTF</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/blog/srdnlenctf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 23:08:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/blog/srdnlenctf/</guid><description>SrdnlenCTF Writeups for srdnlenCTF
Categories Web
I love pickles Challenges I love pickles Category Points Solves Web 50 51 Challenge Description: My Sardinian friend says she hates &amp;ldquo;su cugumere cunfettau&amp;rdquo;, but I love them, on top of my burger and in my code.
If you really know your pickles you can enter in my admin area.
Website: http://ilovepickles.challs.srdnlen.it
Approach As the name of the challenge suggests, the application should use the pickle library to encode and decode the cookies (I found out about this library while I was playing the sekaiCTF, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t solve the challenge there).</description></item></channel></rss>