<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CTFs on Alberto Giust</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/</link><description>Recent content in CTFs on Alberto Giust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 07:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alright21.github.io/ctf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>hpAndro Mobile CTF</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/mobile_hpandro/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/mobile_hpandro/</guid><description>hpAndro Mobile CTF Hello everyone! In this blog post, I will explain how I solved some challenges in hpAndro mobile CTF. I am trying to learn mobile security, and this mobile app helped me to improve my skills, especially on what concern dynamic analysis. I will update this article in the future, so keep an eye on that! Furthermore, I suggest you to try these challenges first on your own, but do not hesitate to look for the solutions if you need it:) And if you have a better solution, feel free to contact me and I will be happy to learn from you!</description></item><item><title>FE CTF 2023</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/fe_ctf_2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 08:58:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/fe_ctf_2023/</guid><description>FE CTF 2023 Write-ups for FE CTF 2023. This weekend I was quite busy, but I managed to solve some easy challenges in this CTF.
Challenges Login - Level 1 Login - Level 2 Login - Level 4 CRACKME.EXE - Level 1 Challenges Login - Level 1 Category Points Solves Web 26 357 Challenge Description So you fancy yourself a hacker? Me? I don&amp;rsquo;t even see the code!
Log in, get flag</description></item><item><title>TCP1P CTF 2023</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/tcp1pctf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 08:53:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/tcp1pctf/</guid><description>TCP1P CTF 2023 Write-ups for TCP1P CTF 2023.
Challenges Intention Challenges Intention Category Points Solves Mobile 356 13 Challenge Description Approach The challenge presents an interesting setup compared to regular mobile challenges: we are asked to create a malicious app that exploits it inside an emulator, great idea!
The application has two activities: MainActivity, where nothing happens, and a FlagSender, where the content of flag.txt file is set as an intent result and sent back to the caller.</description></item><item><title>SrdnlenCTF</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/srdnlenctf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 23:08:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/ctf/srdnlenctf/</guid><description>SrdnlenCTF Writeups for srdnlenCTF
Categories Web
I love pickles Challenges I love pickles Category Points Solves Web 50 51 Challenge Description: My Sardinian friend says she hates &amp;ldquo;su cugumere cunfettau&amp;rdquo;, but I love them, on top of my burger and in my code.
If you really know your pickles you can enter in my admin area.
Website: http://ilovepickles.challs.srdnlen.it
Approach As the name of the challenge suggests, the application should use the pickle library to encode and decode the cookies (I found out about this library while I was playing the sekaiCTF, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t solve the challenge there).</description></item></channel></rss>