<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on Alberto Giust</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on Alberto Giust</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 08:50:38 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://alright21.github.io/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intercepting Traffic in Mobile Flutter Applications</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/blog/mobile_flutter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 08:50:38 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/blog/mobile_flutter/</guid><description>Intercepting Traffic in Mobile Flutter Applications During our tests, it may happen that we have to find vulnerabilities in applications built with the Flutter framework. It is pretty common when we have both Android and iOS apps. This framework raises some problems when we need to intercept traffic for two reasons:
flutter apps are proxy unaware - if we add a proxy listener from the settings of our phone, the application will ignore it flutter apps often implement ssl pinning techniques that are not easily bypassed using standard frida scripts Below are explained the solutions for Android and iOS.</description></item><item><title>Mobile Security Introduction</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/blog/mobile_security/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2023 18:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/blog/mobile_security/</guid><description>Mobile Security Introduction After quite a while, I finally decided to upload this article, and now I have found the courage to do so. If you come across any inconsistencies, I am always open to feedback. I will continuously update it, aiming to create a comprehensive &amp;lsquo;mobile security introduction garden.&amp;rsquo; Have fun reading! :)
Setup Every mobile assessment requires some different setup compared to web applications. In this guide, we will explain how to enter the beatiful world of mobile security, and not feel overwhelmed by do so.</description></item><item><title>SrdnlenCTF</title><link>https://alright21.github.io/blog/srdnlenctf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 23:08:58 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://alright21.github.io/blog/srdnlenctf/</guid><description>SrdnlenCTF Writeups for srdnlenCTF
Categories Web
I love pickles Challenges I love pickles Category Points Solves Web 50 51 Challenge Description: My Sardinian friend says she hates &amp;ldquo;su cugumere cunfettau&amp;rdquo;, but I love them, on top of my burger and in my code.
If you really know your pickles you can enter in my admin area.
Website: http://ilovepickles.challs.srdnlen.it
Approach As the name of the challenge suggests, the application should use the pickle library to encode and decode the cookies (I found out about this library while I was playing the sekaiCTF, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t solve the challenge there).</description></item></channel></rss>